Howdy.
Howdy, howdy.
I'll be back shortly.
I'll be here.
Hello, hello, hello.
Good evening.
Oh, Dave joins us.
Hi.
Hello, hello.
How's going?
It's going good.
Sorry, my brain's half asleep.
I'm just ping Dave.
Dave is still.
Where are you, by the way?
I'm sorry.
Where were you last week?
I was in Zurich on business trip.
Oh, yes.
Your Swedish team.
Your Swiss team.
Sure.
What?
Yeah.
And we got, you know, a lot of nice Swiss chocolate to bring back.
There's a boutique shop halfway across town that I go to rather than the touristy stuff.
My goodness.
So, so wait, so what I really realized is I need to swing by your house.
Sure.
Excellent.
I have several, and you can take your pick.
All right.
I just, he notified me he is on his way.
How are you doing, Wade?
I'm doing fine.
That sounded very unconvincing.
I'm sorry, man.
No, it's all right.
My one co-worker has gotten so bad that I've had to point out to management that he's not pulling his weight at all.
Oh, you have a co-worker, right?
I forgot about that.
I have one whole co-workers, and I'm doing most of his job for him.
Like, I'm literally learning FPGA design as I go and coming out with things that he's not delivering.
And it's just because he's taking, I mean, he just keeps doing it wrong and wronger.
That's so nice of you.
I know.
No, it's great because I'm learning all this stuff.
And that part is fun, but the customer is not happy because, you know, we take a little longer than it should to do the basic tasks.
Anyway, the manager said, like, oh, well, thanks for telling me.
Perhaps you should gently challenge your co-worker.
And I'm like, and you are also dead weight.
I feel like Dave, as your former manager, should be hearing these stories so that he can feel better about his time as your manager.
I just don't have patience for certain types of people.
I know.
Generally, though, so when I was at Roku, right, like the most of the co-workers, you know, possibly today's credit for hiring, but you know, most of our co-workers were pretty great.
I don't think I ever really had an issue until Dave was no longer my boss.
Then, yeah.
Dave, Dave, you're getting some heavy praise here.
I don't, did you catch it?
No.
I think the words were.
I worked with, while I was at Roku working for Dave, I never experienced bad co-workers.
In fact, they were all very good.
It was only when I stopped working for Dave where things went south.
Yeah.
I believe there was also the Dave was not dead weight.
I actually think he was.
No, I think you put him in the more positive category.
Dave was a good boss.
I had my moments.
I am good at my job.
You are.
Yeah.
Well, your friend Rob Zenner was not very professional.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Ghosted me.
Very, very slow in communication.
Many weeks.
And then ultimate ghosting.
Not cool, dude.
Just FYI.
That's really just a thing.
I would encourage you not to send your other friends to him.
Thank you for that feedback.
Absolutely.
That sounds not very happy to hear that.
Thank you.
Not cool.
No, no, I totally agree with you.
I'm
anyway.
I will not be joining this company.
Apparently.
Not that I got a dispositive email or anything.
I'm just, it was clear that was the outcome.
Yeah.
That's kind of shitty.
All right.
Last time we checked, we were in the midst of a battle.
Oh, right.
I should probably open everything.
By the way, I'm still very much in love with this.
This tool.
There's a lot of tools.
Which one are you referring to?
The one that generated the map builder.
Yeah.
They've added a whole bunch of new features to it, and so I started playing with it again.
This is what happens when Costatas has.
Oh, yes.
Yes, I know what my plan is.
You do?
That I made up and met several weeks ago.
Oh, I'm just going to.
Whose turn in the order is it?
Start here, orc one.
It's still loading.
Where are you today, by the way?
I'm in Germany.
He's somewhere where it's 6 a.m.
Oh, you're in Germany?
What are you doing there, man?
Tourism or vacation?
Yeah.
Vacation.
How long are you going to be there for?
We leave on Saturday.
What part of the year?
Try turning on the video and see how the internet speed is.
So far, okay.
It looks fine.
Yeah, it looks okay so far.
Good.
All right.
Orc 6.
What part of Germany?
The north.
It's quite cold, actually.
Quite cold.
A bit chilly this morning.
Last week, Zurich was very rainy, but not cold.
Zurich is a lot further south.
Yeah.
Germany is surprisingly north.
It's actually a lot.
The north of the north.
Yeah, it's actually a lot further north than you think it is.
Yeah.
It's kept warm by the parts of the Gulf Stream.
Otherwise, it would be really freaking cold.
All right.
So, Orc 1.
Okay.
Orc 6.
I'm looking.
No, no.
Orc 6.
Sorry.
I was looking at the 6.
Orc 6.
I am Orc 6.
Orc 6 is dead.
He was in the last campaign.
He had you there.
That was good, Wade.
Confuse the DM metagaming.
I like it.
That was good.
That could work, especially after like a month of not playing.
It wasn't a month.
It was only two weeks.
Three weeks.
Then three weeks.
We missed two sessions.
That's why I'm going to be playing from Greece next week.
6 a.m.
You know, 6 a.m.
No, we'll call it 7 a.m.
No, I'll call.
No, without my socks.
Oh, right.
7 a.m.
You have to start with a Bloody Mary.
What's wrong with that?
Not continental time, Eastern European time.
Yeah, just a mimosa or Bloody Mary.
It's classy.
Mimosa.
Yeah.
Dude, what is it?
Like, why can't these?
Why can't people just do things the old-fashioned way?
Progress, man.
No, that's what they.
All right.
I don't know, whatever.
So I can't seem to find the character.
So he attacks the orc number six.
What does an orc number six do?
Orc number six goes over here and thwacks at the cleric.
Oh, the cleric.
Did he not enter a square that's being threatened?
But if I just moves, yeah, I mean, yes, he did.
So you get to take a swipe at him.
So it was around what was the path, Ken?
He went from here to here.
Oh, that's five feet, though.
So that wouldn't.
Oh, so he stays within five feet of you, right?
Oh, he didn't disengage.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
That makes sense.
Okay, I didn't.
All right, so he's going to swing at Valphine.
Did you see that?
I rolled a 20.
Do not save your roles.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah, I rolled a 20, and I'm trying to find the monster like Master Manual.
AC17.
Yeah, I rolled a 20, so I hit.
I mean, I did, really honestly.
A 20 crit or a 20 with a bonus?
20 with a bonus.
Otherwise, I would have seen critical hit!
I don't know how excited you are to kill your friends.
Wow, that's harsh.
Oh, no, I'm saying I don't.
I would say he's very excited.
I didn't think that was insulting at all.
It's just that I don't know if you can.
All right, five points of damage.
You saw that, right?
Yes, we did.
So, do I do a constitution constitution save or something?
Yes.
Oh, you were on fairy fire, right?
Yeah.
What is my 10.
Is that con save?
Yep.
It looks here like War Caster's.
Oh.
Oops.
Well, no more fairy fire, huh?
No.
Okay.
All right.
Vukradin.
V-dog.
No, there's two Vs.
That doesn't work.
Is that me?
Yes, that would be you, Vukradin.
Okay.
I'm going to cast command, and I'm going to do it with my bardic inspiration.
Oh, my gosh.
What does that do?
First, I will use the Bardic inspiration.
That raises all the difficulties.
That means basically the DC will be increased by two.
All right.
Your role will be reduced by two.
It's the same thing.
And then I will cast command.
Okay.
I haven't seen it.
All right.
So you got to roll 15 or better on the wisdom.
The shaman.
On the shaman.
The currently transformed shaman.
Yeah.
Yep.
All right.
And now I have to go find the shaman's saving throw.
Sorry.
In boar form, no less.
Is it in bore form?
I don't think so.
It sure.
So status says boar 11 HP and he's a boar on the screen.
Yeah, no, no, but I just like when he transforms, what is his saving throws?
Oh, I assume he takes the stats of his shape, but I thought he took this for wisdom save.
He doesn't use his base save for that.
Yes, so I'm rolling his base save.
The statistics are the same in each form.
All right, there.
Makes it easy.
Natural 20.
What?
He's rolling 20s left and right, man.
That's not fair.
At least that one we saw.
True.
At least you saw that one.
I need, do I have something that can negate natural 20s?
No.
Simply.
I don't know.
No diviner this time.
Diviners are really useful sometimes.
Okay, so that was effectively an 18, by the way, but still greater than 13.
Why was it effectively an 18?
Because reduced by two.
Okay.
All right.
So.
So Soma is up.
All right.
Soma.
No need to move.
We're just going to bite and claw on the shaman.
So.
And faerie fire is down.
There's no advantage or anything.
So, yeah, just public roll.
That's five damage on shaman.
All right.
But that takes him to six.
Six hit point.
Yeah.
Yep, six hit point.
Yep.
And then we're going to claw him.
And that is, that'll finish him off.
All right.
Well, that'll take him out of boar form, right?
Yeah, we're back to back to basic form.
Now Brewbarry needs to do 22 hit points in one round.
Good luck.
I tried, guys.
I really did.
Yeah.
This could happen.
Natural 20.
That's gonna have to hit 14 points of damage.
Is that four?
Are you raging?
It should be plus rage.
So that's plus two.
Yeah, for some reason, it doesn't add the friggin rage bonus.
It's plus six points of damage, yeah.
Wow, that is pretty low.
But I at least get a thief into someone nearby.
All right, at least not me.
Number three, uh, sure.
I mean, he's the nearest by ouch.
I think you whiffed.
Wow.
Yeah.
I just would love to know what Valphine means to keep it.
There's nothing we can do if we roll this badly.
Yeah.
Should I then use my bonus action to shove?
Wait.
No.
To shove.
This is not Balter's game.
Oh, he shove.
Okay.
Come on, Shaman.
Take your turn.
I mean, he spent his last turn turning into a boar so he could survive a turn.
Yes, that was.
Oh, right.
Why am I sitting here in this noise?
There we go.
He blasts.
He also blasts one of his allies, though.
So he blasts Brewbarry and Valphine with a lightning bolt.
So 32 points of damage if you're not.
Dear Lord.
Wow.
Okay.
That seems like a shrug-alph thing.
All right.
Valphine makes her saving throw.
She takes 16 points of damage.
Okay.
And Brewbarry has to also make a saving throw.
Brewbarry also makes a saving throw.
So 16.
I think you should try to shrug that damage off.
Okay.
So he takes six points of damage.
Right.
So the rage doesn't give him resistance on that, though.
No, no, only attacking, not against lightning attacks.
Okay.
There are various speats you can acquire later to deal with that.
But yes, apparently.
What's Valphine concentrating on?
Not faerie fire.
Faerie fire.
Okay, so that's cancelled.
Yeah, it was canceled a while ago.
It would have been helpful with all those bad effect rolls.
Yeah.
So orc one is up.
Sorc one is up.
That's a miss, I believe.
Yeah.
On, I mean, you got to say who.
Oh, it's on.
On Valphine.
And Valphine.
That's a miss.
Valphine's armor class.
17.
Yeah, no, that should have been plus 5, but I just got it.
Anyway, so it doesn't matter.
16 was still me a miss.
Okay.
And number 2 and number 4.
Yeah, I'm just going to put them over here so I can keep track of them.
Number 2.
Number 4 is number 2.
4.
Number 4 is going to take a whack at Soma.
What?
No.
Soma, what's your armor class?
15.
That is a miss.
Can't hit the broadside of a bear.
That was number 4.
Number 2 is going to strike Brewbarry.
Your thick fur blocked it.
And rolls a natural one.
Valphine, you're up.
All right.
If I come down here, do I get wait?
What are we doing with advantage in this game?
We're not doing flanking advantage.
No, we're not doing flanking advantage because you have all of your various weapons bonuses.
Okay, alright.
Then I'll.
By the way, enemies don't have advantage either.
All right.
We're going to come over here and.
Which, by the way, is very annoying when you have a horde of orcs.
Attack this number one for six.
Six points of damage.
All right.
He's down to nine hit points.
Oh, maybe I did that here and attacked two instead.
Sorry.
All right.
That's fine.
I was like going, that is a level of tactical awareness that, you know, I just didn't seem very off for you.
Are you okay?
Is everything fine?
Jet lag, so you just couldn't go.
That was very odd.
All right.
Okay.
Orc number three.
Orc number three is going to thwack Brewbarry and misses.
And orc number five.
Well.
Orc number five gets into your zone of danger.
Dang to zone.
All right, then.
And then we'll attack you.
Maybe he won't.
Orc number five.
Oh, no, he's down to four hit points.
Plus three.
One hit point.
Down to one.
One hit point, man.
Makes it over here and screams something in orcish.
Probably along the lines of my mom told me to get a real job.
Right.
So that's a D12 plus three.
Ten points of damage.
Five, actually, because of the you're raging.
Well, that's definitely hurting.
We're cutting down, guys.
The orcs are you guys are I don't think I'll be able to take them on on my own just FYI.
I mean they're they haven't even hit my main hit points yet All right doesn't prove anything Yeah, you and me Wade it's gonna be down number six is dead.
No, number six is dead.
make another saving throw Shaman this time he fails you are halted no action this turn excellent all right no action this round all right well I'm still gonna wail on him all right Soma let's see it he's at 22 yeah well other than movement is there anything else that is there any side effect is it halt is it condition or you get no action so he's not like prone or anything I don't get extra all right same same story he's right there in front of me yes uh that is that's a miss isn't it yeah he's oh my god yeah that was a that's fine second attack oh two misses go bear goes the shaman that won't die Brewbarry at least he won't uh yeah three and five could be killed all right let's get customers a few more 20s to round this out so at least we have averages all right and i can't cleave because i missed that's my understanding of the rules all right orc one okay this guy the orc one attacks Valphine and misses guys i gave you a whole round to like kill this guy and you did nothing exactly zero um misses Valphine you're up all right um can i do anything actually useful um you've got guys with one hit point you can like try hit kill but three and five have one hit point each this is a side effect i i think i have to do something a little bit more interesting like
that
all right who are you targeting the shaman all right the shaman's down to 10 points of damage and the cutting bolt gets the next attack advantage yes uh yeah i would give Vukradin a bonus so Vukradin you need to like use an attack on the shaman all right well i mean number 50 Soma right
oh yeah you're right you're right yeah it's just whoever attacks next it's not the next attack it's whoever attacks next all right uh orc number three uh attacks Brewbarry again this guy attacks Brewbarry again hits uh plus five yeah it's an 18.
so i think we're gonna knock you out Brewbarry yes you are knocked out or down to one hit point you are minus you're at zero you can't truck or anything i did that all right right on the lightning bolt of doom all right yeah Vukradin you're up
That is a hit.
No, it's not a hit.
It's a save.
That's a wisdom save on command against the shaman.
That is a blown save.
You're going to make her flee.
Flea another halt.
You're not going to make her flee.
So what's his name?
Gets weapons of opportunity?
He's down.
I would get one, but yeah, I would make as much use of it as you would have.
All right.
Soma, you're going to.
You don't trust Soma and Brewbarry to finish the job.
Then start doing damage yourself.
So what was the condition on him?
Halted.
No, what did Valphine put down?
I guided Vault, so you get advantage.
You have advantage on your first attack.
First attack.
Okay, let me make sure I do the right one.
1d8 plus 4 or 2d6 plus 4.
Obviously, 2d6 plus 4 will be advantage.
All right.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
You killed.
Oh, and then my attacks don't actually have to be on the same target.
So yeah, let's go ahead and bite number four.
We've got number three and five are at one hit.
Oh, nice.
Somebody who has.
Can you make it to three or five?
I don't.
Yeah, you can.
Yeah, I can come around this way.
No, you can walk over them.
They're dead bodies.
Are you going to stand on top of me, too?
I don't want to teabag you.
They're five feet.
Remember, five feet, bodies, you know, there's lots of free space.
Yeah, but I'm big.
All right, then, yeah, I would have done it on the number who's the next to attack at one hit point.
We number three.
Number three that is dead.
Yeah.
All right.
So number three is dead.
Orc one.
Another quick one.
No, Brewbarry.
Brewbarry is up.
Oh, Brewbarry is down.
Brewbarry is down.
Death save.
Brewbarry, two death saves.
Win and a loss.
All right.
Okay.
Orc number four.
Come at me, bro.
Orc number one, rather.
Orc number one.
Number one has still not been hit.
So he's going to screams something about
something about Talos.
If you make a religion check, I will tell you what it is.
Sure.
Oh, he gets a critical on Valphine.
That's bad.
He's a cleric of Talos.
Wait, he was.
Cleric of Talos?
No, they're followers of Talos.
Oh, Talos.
I will get you that information in a second.
You take 14 points of damage, Valphine.
Valphine's down too.
All right.
Oh, we really are going to have to finish them off together.
Okay.
That's fine.
It's just the dregs now.
The drags.
Well, we killed the load-bearing boss.
So Orc 5 then?
Misses.
All right.
Valphine, death save.
Two death saves.
We only hope here is we can finish them off before the death saves run out.
Okay, one and one should be able.
Right.
Orc.
No, or oh, orc five first.
Okay, orc five is down to one hit point.
So he is going to make like a he's going to disengage and run this way.
Oh, he actually disengages.
All right.
Oh, no, he isn't.
I'm just telling you what he did.
You can do whatever you want.
Yeah.
Only one hit point.
Just keep that in mind.
I'm working on it.
Oh, yeah, it is your turn now.
All right, dead.
Bye-bye, Orc5.
Good time to crit.
On the fleeing one-hit point guy.
On the fleeing one-hit point.
That's what we were saving our natural 20s for, guys.
Good job.
All right.
You know, Soma doesn't really approve of senseless killing like that.
She doesn't?
No.
They're running away.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Yeah, that does sound like unbranded for Soma.
She's not a fan of killing, fleeing, even orcs, but whatever.
Hey, Soma.
Yeah.
They're not like animals.
So they're not animals.
They're trying to assassinate us, and they will come back and try to kill us again.
This is not a, like, they're not neutral.
They can learn their law.
This isn't about getting their treasure.
It's about saving our lives.
Well, that guy was not a threat to us anymore.
You shot him in the back.
Anyway.
He was going to be a threat to us.
We have already explained at the end of the combat.
Yes, yes.
All right.
Talking may be a free action, but it wastes everybody's time.
Yes.
I guess we're going to work on two on number four first.
This should do it in this order.
Awesome.
All right.
We'll do the other one.
That's a kill.
It's a kill on four.
Nice.
Yes.
All right.
Vukradin.
No, orc.
Orc one.
Orc one is up.
Well, orc one, seeing that you killed his buddy, realizes that he, you know, life isn't.
He has no choice but.
Would he like to surrender?
Can we tag Fork four as dead, please?
Would he like to surrender and be interrogated?
No.
You killed a shaman.
You killed the shaman.
You killed the guy who was running away.
I mean, he's kind of convinced.
It's either it's the consequences of me killing the guy who was running away.
This is what happens, man.
You also get a reputation.
You also expose to so much.
I'm going to get a reputation.
Yeah, right.
It's us.
Who's going to come to your show?
I've already got a reputation.
That's a hit.
Who did he hit?
You.
Oh, Vukradin.
Me, Vukradin.
All right.
How many hit points do I have?
Not many.
Poke the bear.
21.
All right.
You got 10 damage?
How much damage did you do?
10 damage.
And you're Vukradin, you're up.
All right, Vukradin goes first.
Sorry.
Oh, I'm up.
And like, he's right there.
He's in your face.
Oh, I have two daggers, and I shall use them.
Attack one.
That is all right.
For six.
All right.
And then attack two.
Crit.
Six points.
You're still alive.
That's all right.
I got two chances to do three damage.
Not 93.
Three.
Yeah, two chances to do.
Oh, I didn't see this.
Yeah.
All right, Soma, you're up.
Yeah, I'll just roll them both.
I'm not even going to wait to see the result.
Nope.
There we go.
There's a kill.
Okay.
That was an intense combat.
We beat their death saves.
I would like to announce what I do next.
Oh, okay.
I am convinced that the pin was what led the monsters to us.
I'm going to take the pin.
I'm going to break it in two, and I'm going to plant it on the field as though it was destroyed during the combat.
Oh, the thing you got from the sword and shield people or whatever?
Yes, from Sir Wants to Kill Me.
Okay, so that's your deep-seated period.
I'm convinced that that was what led these assassins to us.
Okay.
Do you want to look over any of the bodies or anything?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But also, I'm dumping the pen in a way that makes it look like I didn't dump the pen.
Make it look like an accident.
It just fell off.
It's an accident.
Okay.
I mean, you did get, you know, an orc in your face.
You could definitely say that he, you know, punched your, you know, your pocket or whatever.
Exactly.
All right.
Yeah, we can search the body.
Sure.
I mean, can we also stand up our patriots?
Yeah, I'm assuming they're all.
Oh, yeah, everybody's fine.
But this is 50.
You know, guys, we're not going to be taking their treasure.
That's blood money.
Shooting in the back?
Okay.
Taking treasure.
Not okay.
Now you're understanding.
They didn't get that treasure legitimately.
That was stolen.
They got that starry whispin' their back legitimately.
No, that was legit.
He trying to kill me was legit.
It was him acting legitimately, but that treasure didn't belong to him.
Got that, DM?
Look, as far as I'm telling you, I'm telling the party what treasure they find, whether they choose to pick it up or not is their business, not mine.
Just so we're on the same page, right?
Like, as far as I'm concerned, yeah, you guys, I just roll.
I just, I'm just the, I'm the, I roll the treasure.
Treasure duffs.
Here we go.
I need to put this in my direct.
All right.
So you find, well, do you want to know which find or not?
Well, we can add it to blood money.
That's fine.
We can at least see what it is.
Yeah.
So you can also write his new loot.
You're tempting me, Satan.
Six platinum pieces.
Find that.
That's a cute roll-off.
Okay.
One gold.
We'll work on telling that.
Oh, it's six gold piece.
All right.
You can.
And what else do you find?
Is that six platinum?
Yes, it is.
You also find.
Oh, right.
The anthropology of Talos.
And.
Oh, is someone else telling the money?
I've got it here.
I've added it.
You've heard it.
Okay.
All right.
Talos.
So
Valphine, who's got a passing familiarity with the evil gods of Faerûn.
Right.
Probably my neighbors.
A passing familiarity notes that Talos is the deity of storms and destruction.
Why, yes.
His dogma, it demands uttered obedience from his priests and instructing them to spread destruction where they might.
So, you know, right.
So Sir Watts's name did this to us.
And Ser Kaelen.
He's not Ser Kaelen as well.
Or what's his name?
Ser Kaelen.
It was Ser Kaelen.
Yeah.
Ser Kaelen.
That's right.
Oh, God, here it comes.
What are you going to refer to him as a care?
I'm fine with Ser Kaelen.
Ser Kaelen is fine.
That's what we had three weeks ago.
All right.
So the people of an ancient Ithuriel.
Okay, so and is in fact, according to some, an aspect of the orcish god Grumps.
All right.
Apparently, he inspires worship in those who fear the destructive power of nature.
I mean, nature's got its moments.
So is this just an isolated band of orcs, or is this like something that is more?
Well, they had said something, right?
We heard them say something that they knew we were coming and that they had been told we were easy prey.
They literally set up a trap, too, right?
Like, who knew we were coming?
The only two people who knew we were coming were Ser Kaelen and the town master.
Those are the only two.
How do you trust the rest of us, huh?
Wow.
He's had the.
I guess people are starting to wake up.
Yeah, that was pretty rude.
I'm not the other five.
Oh, you woke somebody up.
That's a bummer.
Hold on.
You'd also find some clues.
Oh, wrong, wrong, wrong, wrong.
So there are only two people who knew we were coming.
Plus us.
Right, so it seems pretty clear-cut to me.
Corin, who had been hiding, shows up with you guys.
Right.
Corin.
That's Corin.
Surely he could have finished off with one hit point work.
Oh, yeah, he totally could have, but he was too busy making sure that none of your equipment that he was protecting got hurt.
Thank you, Corin.
Good boy.
Well done.
Sorry.
Ah, no, this is not.
I was looking for something.
Hold on.
Yes, I was just looking for a clue.
I have a clue here.
I need to find it.
All right.
So you find an item that is unusually well made, not typical of orcish craftsmanship.
So
let me just see what we see.
Among the supplies, among the weapons of the ambushing on the Talos cultist, you find a few items that seem unusually well made or bare well made.
Roll an investigation.
Okay.
Ah, yeah, I'm good at this.
12.
Anybody roll?
You got a 4, 5, 6, and 12.
4, 5, 6.
Where is the investigative?
Okay, so there seems something odd.
You notice this, like, amongst all of the orca stuff, there's this thing that looks like it was very well packaged together, sealed in some way, but you can't seem to notice anything odd about it.
You didn't have Corin look at it as well, so he can also take a look at it.
I don't know what his investigation is.
10.
Does it open?
Well, you can pull it apart.
Yes, it does open.
It's like a rat.
It's like a.
So we look at it carefully.
It's like a ration pack that somebody carefully wrapped together.
Okay, Corin rolled an 18.
He looks pale.
Pale.
You know, like frightened, pale.
Like, Ark of the Covenant, pale.
Maybe he can open it.
Oh, no.
Well, he's like, you know, he opens it gladly and then starts eating the food.
But what does it make him pale?
Well, you should ask him.
What is this, Corin?
Corin.
Hold on.
Let me just get this.
So let me just go here.
All right.
So Corin.
Okay.
All right.
So see.
So, Roll, Roll, are you going to try to persuade him or try to intimidate him or just be polite to him when you ask the question?
I don't understand.
I thought Corin was our ally.
Yeah.
Is he not on our side?
He picked up the package and looked pale.
He has his own motives and his own goals.
I mean, if he doesn't want to join our party, I suppose that's fine.
He can just go.
No, no, he does want to join your party.
He's happy to eat it, but you're asking what he saw.
I'm asking how you're asking the question.
That's what I'm saying.
Friendly.
Are you being friendly?
I think we're friendly with him, just generally.
He's been maintaining camp for us, right?
He's like part of our party.
He's our camp cook or whatever.
That's useful.
Right.
Okay.
So.
Also, it costs very little to be nice.
It costs very little to be nice.
He goes, oh, it's just I've never seen something so well packaged among orcs.
It's almost as if somebody gave it to them.
I wouldn't know who, though.
And it is tasty food.
Better than the usual crap you find amongst orcs.
Oh, yes.
That sounds like an excellent idea.
Wait.
What kind of food?
He pulls out some typical rations.
It's like clearly much better than the orcs would eat.
Obviously, this is why the shaman had it.
Probably kept it for himself.
It was probably payment for the attack.
Orcs are always looking for food.
Do orcs normally save food?
I figure they just eat it before, you know, coming out here.
Well, who knows when they got it?
You know, maybe this was like the 23rd pack of rations.
I have no idea.
But it's quite tasty.
Would you like some?
Sure.
That's exactly what it is: rations.
There's nothing distinctive about the packaging.
As you pick it up, you notice on as so you take up the packaging and you look at it, you notice there's a distinctive C on it.
The letter C.
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Ser Kaelen with a Circle friend.
Yeah, you also, because this would have only been two days ago in real time, but in game time, but like not three weeks ago in real time, you also recall that there's a local bandit chief called the Carver around.
Oh, right.
Carver.
That's sort of floating in our quests.
The carver was.
Well, Corin was working for the Carver, right?
Yes.
So.
Does he recognize the C as the Carver's label?
Or monogram or whatever?
He looks at it and goes, Yes, yes, this is very much the Carver's monogram.
I don't know how it slipped.
Ser Kaelen is in cahoots with the Carver.
Ser Kaelen is the Carver.
Oh.
You ever seen him in the same room at the same time?
Well, he goes, I've never actually seen the Carver, so I suppose I'm looking for it.
Wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
So you've never actually seen the Carver.
So you always work for an intermediary?
Yes.
That guy you killed who was in charge of my band, I was working for him.
And, you know, I was hired.
If only we hadn't killed everyone.
I offered to want to put it in.
We did say we did spare Corin.
You're right.
All right.
So, yes.
So there's apparently Corin.
Corin has you have found a clue that suggests that the orcs
were.
All right, guys.
So
I have an idea.
If we're being tracked to the lighthouse, maybe we should change direction.
Are we still going to go to the lighthouse though?
Maybe we should go do something else.
We did kind of, you know, you're close enough to the lighthouse that you can make it in an hour or so.
Well, so at the very least, we need to rest.
There could be another trap.
There could be another trap waiting for us.
Yeah.
I definitely need to rest.
But you don't like being at death save hit points.
Yeah, I think we should long rest overnight at this location.
Not here.
At least find a more secure area.
Nearby.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you take a long rest.
Yay.
Wild shape charge restored.
Long rest, recharge.
And, you know, more than an hour has passed, so I go back to Valphine.
So, just as a side note, you have your portal?
Yeah.
All right.
So, just as you continue on your journey towards the tower, can you put us on the world map, please?
Oh, yes, of course.
That's better.
So, we are tower of storms.
It's a lighthouse.
Yeah.
You're like five, seven miles away, so like an hour's walk.
What?
Couldn't we come from over here?
Yes.
We were all the way around the coast, which is a weird path to have been.
That's all.
No, no, I just moved.
You crossed into the tower of this area over here.
Yeah, okay.
That's where the right.
And so you said you moved, so I moved you.
That's all.
We should take a circuitous route if we're going to go there, like maybe come from the south.
So these are like cliffs on the entry?
Yes.
I think the same way the, what you'll call it, the, the, if you go to the coast here on the, you know, to the Pacific, it's kind of like that.
Cliffs with sometimes beaches and so on and so forth.
It's our rocks.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you take a circuitous, stealthy route this time rather than following the obvious path.
Well, I mean, Vukradin brings up a good point.
Should we head somewhere else?
Or are we going to the tower that everybody knows we're going to?
I think we should still go.
We should just approach from the south.
Okay.
Yeah.
We told people we were going to do this.
I mean, traps aside, our words were something.
I think we will be more secretive in the future.
Yeah.
Not declaring where you're going all the time, bragging about it.
Well, it's.
We weren't bragging.
We were researching, but not, you know.
Trying to help people, and this is what happens to us.
It's not very nice.
Gary, there's a cat on your shoulders.
Yeah, there's a cat over here.
Corin mentions, turns to you guys and says, I don't know if it was Ser Kaelen, but the Carver has agents in the village.
Really?
He doesn't want us to be suspicious against the.
What?
He doesn't want us to be suspicious against the wrong person?
Who are the agents?
He goes, I don't know.
How did you identify yourself to your intermediaries?
They found me on the.
I didn't have a secret handshake or code.
No, I didn't.
Did you have something on your lapel?
No, we didn't have pins like the Lord of the Order of the Gauntlet or like the Harpers or tattoos like the Zentarim.
Really, or chains of office like the Lord's Alliance.
We were bandits.
I got the.
He looks at the armor, looks at you.
I was gifted armor.
Oh, the armor.
Well, the person who gave it to you did not have it rightfully.
Yes, but I was gifted.
I did not steal this armor.
This was a gift.
Well, it's like if you buy a stolen car, it doesn't mean you own the car now.
Yes, well, I think this was a gift.
If you are gifted a stolen car, you do not own cars.
I don't know.
Okay, this could go on.
Corin realizes this could be circuitous.
All right.
So you arrive at the Tower of the Swarms.
These kids.
Let's see, where is it?
Someone.
Hmm?
Ah, there we go.
Just rubbined.
Okay.
No key dokeems.
Brewbarry, Valphine and Soma.
Alright.
So you arrive on the coast.
Dave, you're still there?
Oh, okay.
And we're still on the world map, if that matters.
Oh, thank you for telling me that.
Never sure.
Yes, well.
Alright, we have Tower of Storms.
You arrive on the coast.
There we go.
Dach.
You know, let me just do something.
I'm going to just give me...
Give me one second.
Let me just.
Alright, well.
So, just this is very unfortunate, but the...
Right back in like two minutes.
Okay.
So the thing on the right hand is a blow-up of the castle, but you should, like, there's a.
Here, let me just.
You guys see that?
There's like this tower you can see.
Make sense?
You see that?
Uh, not really.
Okay.
Hold on.
Sorry, you guys is not at the resume level.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's.
There we go.
Explore mode.
There, that's what I want.
Okay.
So.
You see this?
Okay, sure.
Right.
So.
So you sort of see this.
Sort of what you see.
You sort of see this island, and on it is a lighthouse.
There is a path leading down into this rock outcropping, and that will lead you directly to the lighthouse.
You can also see destroyed boats off in the distance near the lighthouse itself.
Alright.
Okay.
Below the high cliffs that hugs the coastline, an outcropping of rock is nearly surrounded by water with only a natural causeway connecting it to the beach below.
Atop this outcropping is a stone building surmounted by a loudhouse tower.
An eerie green light pulses from this beacon shining westward out to sea.
With each green pulse of life, light, you hear the thump of a slow beating heart.
Thank you.
Sorry about that.
No, it's fine.
All right.
So there's a beach on the beach.
There on the beach, you can see a crab of monstrous size, and there's a pathway that will lead to the building.
What a coincidence.
I literally just finished reading Night of the Crabs.
After we're done.
Okay.
No reason to check the crab out first.
Well, I mean, if it's monster crab, then it's alive, right?
Well, you.
I mean, I can go talk with it.
Actually, we can talk into the animals.
I'm going to go take it with animals or something.
Yeah, no, I'm totally going to try to engage it in conversation because, you know, maybe it'll tell us there's a trap ahead.
I'm pretty sure.
Who votes for Ser Kaelen and the Carver?
Dude, you'd be surprised what animals know.
I'm 90% sure I put speak with animals on my characters.
As he approaches you, as you approach the crab, the crab says, well met.
Wait, the crab speaks common?
Yes, I speak common.
What?
I don't even need to speak with animals.
Hello.
Before you cast the spell, he sort of says, well met.
Well, yeah, I guess I avoid it.
I don't cast it.
Like, hello.
I just surprised you to talk a crab.
Yes, as you're about to cast it, he says, well met, which causes you to sort of like.
It knocks, you know, catches me off guard.
Right, because what brings you to this part of the mountains?
You know, we just heard there was a cursed lighthouse over here.
I'm sure you've seen a bunch of wreckage around, right?
Oh, yes.
What can you tell us about it?
Well, he looks at you, goes, it's and yeah, it's been such a wonderful day.
See, oh, about the about the lighthouse.
That's what you were asking about.
Well, I mean, the lighthouse, obviously, you have to have seen some of the wrecks in action, right?
Right, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
What's causing them?
He goes, well, there's some evil harpies which nest atop the rocky outcropping.
That might be it.
Harpies are just taking out ships?
Well, they do that.
That sounds like a little too much for some harpies.
Well, I don't actually know why people keep crashing their boats here.
There's five shipwrecks which are spread around the rock beneath the lighthouse.
I'll fetch the treasure for you if you help me.
Help you out.
Mind if I go help the crab?
I got water breathing and stuff.
Well, she goes, there's a shark in those waters.
So you can deal with it afterwards.
I actually probably can.
Hold on.
Dawes?
Dawes is in the waters.
That's a big point.
I mean, this is Circle of the Moon.
I have access to a lot of crazy shit.
Well, what can you tell us about the shark while I'm looking this one up just to see?
Okay, so he goes, but before I helped you with the treasure, I do need you to do me a good deed, if you would be so kind.
And what is your name again?
They call me Soma.
Soma?
You do look.
Tall.
Not that tall.
Wait, Soma, is that not your real name?
Well, that's my real name.
Oh, okay.
I'm pretty just the way you phrased it.
Yeah.
We're creating a crab.
Okay, now we have this new angle.
I'm getting really suspicious about all the things that are going on.
I'm starting to get a little bit paranoid.
Well, sorry.
We'll roll an insight check on the crab.
Is it lying to us?
No, it is not lying to you.
I trust this crab.
All right.
Is TND Reynolds not responding for other people?
No, it's responding for other people.
No, it's working.
All right.
So the crab.
Okay, so it says, My.
I will bring you a great weapon.
Okay.
That seems great.
All right.
It's plus one weapon.
From the wreck of the star-crossed lover from one of the ships, she says, and she says, but I need you to help me lay to rest my dead sea, the elf that brought me, that gifted me my intelligence.
I can respect that.
A burial ceremony?
Well, it's a little bit more complicated than a burial ceremony.
So she kind of lifts her claws up and goes, it's a little bit smart.
A crab can't do air quotes.
A little bit.
Crab kind of lifts up its two craws.
Well, it puts its claws down, twitches its thing, and goes, She's a little bit of a spirit now, and she haunts the cave.
And so let me just tell you where the cave is.
I can do an octopus.
That's probably useful.
And she goes, Meryl.
You should see Meryl right now.
I'm going to take a mural, right?
Oh, no.
The same Meryl?
No, no, not the same Meryl.
No, that did not work.
No, that's why I didn't put it.
It's wrong layer.
So she says,
should see that where there's like a.
Do you see Miral?
Ghost Cel.
Oh, Mural, ghosts, sea elf.
All right.
So it says, yes, I would need you to go take care of her.
Could you go put her to rest?
She's tormented by something or other.
So she's not quite dead.
Well, that's why they said it's a little bit more tricky.
Valphine, you want us to weigh in on this?
So, like, do I think I can turn dead on it's not about turning on dead.
It's the ghost.
So just so you just in case you missed it or I mangled it, the crab is basically saying that her mistress, Meral, rather the elf, sorry, the person who turned her into a sentient elf died and has become undead and is a ghost and needs to have something done so that she will move on to the next life.
Okay.
Is she aggressive?
The ghost?
Yeah.
We haven't met the ghost yet.
We can ask the crab, is the ghost aggressive?
What does aggressive mean?
If we walk in there, you know, to help carry her to the beyond, is she going to be grateful by our presence or threatened by it?
Um.
She goes, well, if you do it.
So the crab goes, well, it's what I have noticed is that when you pass by Miral's cave, she'll ask you to take on this quest of hers.
And if you at least try, she doesn't try to kill you, but if you say you will, she'll let you live and go by.
So all I'm asking is that you, you know, actually fulfill the terms of passage.
Okay, what's the question she gives you?
What's the class she gives you?
Yeah.
Well, I don't know.
I can't say that I've overheard.
I've just, you know, seen a few people that went in there, and there was some screaming and some dead bodies.
And this is your ex-lover?
He did say Mr.
No, don't.
Is everything like thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump, thump?
Do I look like the kind of person that wants to have that?
No, she was the elf that blessed me with my intelligence.
I was but a dumb mute crab.
Have you not gone to visit her ghost form?
I mean, you said you've never heard the class, you've never talked to her in this.
Well, it's he goes, it's a little bit tricky for me to go in there.
It's a tiny little hole.
So it has to fit through this thing, and the crabs kind of.
And, well, you know, I you're a little big.
I'm a little big, and I also see.
Well, I'm scared.
Now, why are you scared?
I don't want to see Miral in her ghostly form.
I want to remember her as she was.
And starts crying.
They're there.
Oh, this is about a shark.
Apparently, these are shark-infested waters.
Yes, yes, but if you deal with Miral, I'll bring you the best stuff.
Don't worry.
Oh, you're going to bring us all the lost treasure?
Yes, yes.
And we can find its rightful owner, Vukradin.
Yeah, well, that's.
We're going to need to figure out who the rightful owners are.
It's certainly not the bottom of the sea.
Because it's not the crabs.
Yes.
It's not the sea.
He goes, it's the crab sort of looks at you, pauses pensively.
I have been told that adventurers, you are adventurers, will generally do things for me.
I'm a musician.
I'm a tour guide.
I'm a drow.
In the sun, no less.
Yes, this crab does not look at you and goes, you are a very oddly looking elf.
I'm very normal where I come from.
I see.
Well, every elf, everyone is different.
Anyway, when you come back, just give me a note.
I'll be here playing with the waves or maybe walking along the seashore trying to find something to eat.
And then the crab walks off onto the beach.
All right.
Do you guys want to continue down the path line?
I guess we told the crab we would.
Oh, you just deleted me.
Here, that's fine.
No, no, I.
Wait, I saw two of you.
I only see zero of me.
Oh, good grief.
I know what the problem is.
A bug in the renderer.
Sorry.
What happened was that I've got to do the ghost lover in the whole quest and kill the harpies.
Is that the idea?
No.
Yeah.
We don't have to.
We get to.
Which do we want to do first?
Ghost or the harpies?
It feels like the ghost is in front of us.
Right.
So who's going to be in front?
I'll take the lead.
I always know.
About our cleric.
Okay.
All right.
So.
Come behind me.
I would like to have the cleric nearby, yes.
All right.
Oh, there I am.
And so, a.
Let me see if I can.
All right.
Okay.
Darling storm locations.
All right.
So, Roughstone, the rough hewn steps climb a seven-foot-high tunnel that passes all the way through a 30-foot-tall natural pillar of rock.
A damp, eight-foot-high cave encrusted with lynching is connected to this lichen, is connected to this tunnel.
Hey, we can see that.
The cave remains.
Right.
What is the vegetarian?
In NetHack, you eat lichen in the first few levels to, you know.
Okay.
No, I didn't.
That's good use of NetHack reference there.
The cave remains above sea level at high tide, at high tide.
A ghostly elf with gills manifests itself with webbed hands and webbed feet, wearing spectral garments that sway as though the elf is floating underwater.
So
she sees you.
I am.
Your friend sent us.
My friend?
Who?
Your lover.
The crab.
You know, we actually didn't read the crab's name, did we?
Was it Krabby?
Krabby.
Seeker crabs.
I don't know.
The crab, an intelligent crab that you felt that's feeling particular loyalty to, and though you could.
So, because, oh, yes.
He was a good friend.
Still in his turns.
He goes, I was killed by Mesco.
Moesco.
Moesco?
What?
Do we know that?
No, the Order of the Gauntlet are the good guys.
I don't know about that one.
All right.
She goes, I think they're going to be.
Moesco.
Well, I mean, she goes, but this is not important.
What's important is there's more important things.
And I am responding to my to.
What is your name?
She asks you what your name is.
So do you tell Wade?
Yeah, sure.
All right.
So, Soma, can you see us?
Yeah, I can see.
Okay, it's because for a minute there, you were so motionless that I was like, going to see you.
Oh, no, I just.
So he goes, he says, she says, Moesco is a cleric of Talos.
Oh, more of them.
Yes.
And he stole my conch.
It's like a Lord of the Flies reference.
Yes, I don't know if to.
Apparently, he goes, it was my spell casting focus.
An opalescent conch.
He now possesses it as a trophy.
And I am cursed to stay here and to demand that people, as they walk through here, retrieve the trophy.
And if they don't, you kill them?
Yes.
Sure.
What?
Excellent.
In that case, may the blessings of the sea gods be with you.
Hold on.
Do you know anything about the Carver?
And is there any relation to this Talos clan?
The Carver.
Just curious if she does.
That is a good question.
Because the orcs that were paid off by the Carver were also screaming Talos.
And so, you know.
I have concerns that they're related.
Yeah, maybe she's seen some orcs go by.
Okay.
Well, she pauses and said, well, of course I've seen orcs.
The cleric is a shaman of Talos, and he's a orc.
So she goes, no, I don't know.
So what she says is she goes, the cultists of the Talos, Moesko, invaded my tower.
This is typically more sophisticated planning than orcs have.
Suggesting that there is someone else orchestrating their moves.
Some organization.
But whether it was the Carver or some higher, more powerful, evil cultist, I do not know.
But what I do know.
So, what I do know is that they had strange what Moesko had a strange weapon that I had never seen before.
And it was with that weapon that he defeated me.
And that weapon cursed you, presumably.
That's more.
Well, I died.
Sorry, you did.
But before you die, you saw the weapon.
Yes, I did.
It was of odd construction, like nothing I'd ever seen before.
And it pulsated with magic and something else.
Like a wand or like a sword?
It was used as a sword, I suppose, but it didn't look like any sword I'd ever seen before.
Was it bladed at all?
Let me leave the description.
Hold on.
Okay, so he does say she pauses and thinks about it.
No, no, no, no, that was wrong.
That's not what I remember.
I'm sorry, it's been a while.
What I remember was that he was missing a heart.
Moesko was missing a heart?
Yes.
Yes, he was missing his heart.
There was a hole where his heart was.
In fact, the thing that killed you.
Yes, yes, yes.
In fact, now I remember what draw me here.
It was the pulsing green beacon.
I was curious as to what had happened.
This was not the normal color of the tower.
And so I came to look into it.
And when I looked into it, I encountered Moesko, and Moesko killed me.
And I remember when I was fighting him, he had no heart.
Okay.
A little creepy.
What did you roll, Gary?
I forgot and rolled a seven nature.
You know nothing.
As usual.
I am curious if I know this to be a common ritual of Talos of some sort.
The answer is not.
I did not know this.
No, you do not know.
All right.
Okay.
She goes, well, I hope to see.
She pauses and says, Excellent.
Well, it's so good to see that you have decided to help me in my quest to return back to my blessed sleep and bring me my conch.
Okay.
I wish you all the best.
Do you continue?
Presume.
Sure.
All right.
Okay.
Could you move Soma?
Because I was like, I've got these two sons.
It sounds like some sort of undead, don't you think?
All right, cool.
Valphine?
You asked, does this Talos Priest seem like he's undead?
Yeah.
There's something fishy going on.
One usually needs a heart to live.
Yep.
Here, I'll do medicine.
That should help, right?
No.
Hey, I got advantages on medicine.
Come on, I ran.
Usually, a heart's required.
Maybe, maybe not.
All right.
I can tell you, hearts are good for life.
Yes.
Thanks, Soma.
Took me a long time to learn that.
Okay, so you climb up the tower.
Taking the path, why don't I just go spider and scramble up?
Leave everyone up.
All right.
So you climb up the tower.
Okay.
Wait, I'm so.
Oh, so we don't have to go into the cave.
No, well, you kind of, what do you mean, don't have to go into the cave?
I thought the quest was inside the cave.
Just the ghost is in the cave.
Yes.
And then he sends us to the tower where the harpies are.
See, yes.
And this thing.
And the dead guy, yeah.
All right.
So as you're climbing up, as you're about to make it, as you turn over here, right?
The last switch.
Yes.
And it's like the three harpies.
The harpies have arrived.
Okay.
Harpies have arrived.
And
do they look pissed?
Well, no, but they do look hungry.
All right.
So the harpies fly out to see you.
They saw you as you were coming up.
What do harpies do?
All right.
So all right.
So as you're making, you're making, you're coming around here, the harpies start to sing.
So make some wisdom saving throws.
Oh, no.
Oh, well.
All right.
Valphine, Vukradin, Soma.
Hey, there's our 20s.
All right.
Vukradin and Brewbarry are charmed.
Can we just slap them out?
You mean Valphine and Brewbarry?
Valphine and Brewbarry.
Sorry.
Vukradin is the DC?
11.
Okay.
Yeah, Vukradin's fine.
All right.
So, yeah, I saw you rolled a 20.
That's fine.
Oh, no.
Sorry.
Oh, that was...
I was doing my initiative role.
All right.
Okay, sorry.
So the harpies have charmed Valphine.
Sorry.
Valphine and Brewbarry.
Oh, right.
All right.
That lasts only as long as they can hear the song.
Yes.
So, and the harpies sort of like start.
The two of the harpies are singing, and the third harpy is, you know, you're going to try to sing again.
So can you guys see the harpies or is it the damn fog of messing with us?
We can't even see around the switchback.
Yeah, I'm going to fix this.
There.
Now I can see three harpies.
Yeah.
I'm going to fix that.
Yeah, that's pretty good.
Yeah, it's a lot better.
All right, there.
Sorry, that this Fog of War was irritating.
Doing initiatives?
Yes, we should do initiatives.
So let me just give some numbers to these tokens.
One, two, three.
All right.
Okay.
All righty.
And we are out of time, so we will start next week with the harpies.
Let me just do the initiatives.
I will start with my silent spell.
Yes.
Okay.
Bye, guys.
All right.
Next week, I will be logging in from Greece.
We will be playing DD from my house in Greece.
Have fun.
All right.
Take care.
Have a good evening.
Have a good week, y'all.
Have a good week.